What I wanted to talk to you about today is two things:
اريد اليوم ان اتحدث عن شيئين :
one, the rise of a culture of availability;
اولا، الزيادة فى ثقافة الوفرة ،
and two, a request.
و ثانياً ، طلب
So we're seeing a rise of this availability
نحن نشهد ارتفاعا فى الوفرة
being driven by mobile device proliferation,
بسب انتشار الاجهزة النقالة ،
globally, across all social strata.
على الصعيد العالمي ، في جميع الطبقات الاجتماعية.
We're seeing, along with that proliferation of mobile devices,
نحن نرى ، بالإضافة إلى انتشار الأجهزة النقالة ،
an expectation of availability.
توقع سياسة التوفر.
And, with that, comes the third point,
ويأتى مع هذا ، نقطة ثالثة ،
which is obligation -- and an obligation to that availability.
وهى واجب -- واجب تجاة هذا التوفر.
And the problem is, we're still working through,
والمشكلة هى، اننا ما زلنا نبحث عن طريق ،
from a societal standpoint,
من الناحية الاجتماعية ،
how we allow people to be available.
كيف نسمح للاشخاص أن يكونوا متاحين.
There's a significant delta, in fact,
هناك دلتا كبيرة ، في الواقع ،
between what we're willing to accept.
بين ما نحن على استعداد لقبوله--
Apologies to Hans Rosling --
إعتذار لهانز روزلنج
he said anything that's not using real stats is a lie --
لقد قال أن أي شيء بدون استخدام إحصائيات هو كذب --
but the big delta there
ولكن الدلتا الكبرى هنا
is how we deal with this from a public standpoint.
هو كيف نتعامل مع هذا من الناحية العامة.
So we've developed certain tactics and strategies
لذا قمنا بتطوير بعض التكتيكات والاستراتيجيات
to cover up.
للمواكبة .
This first one's called "the lean."
الاستراتيجية الاولى تدعى " الإنحناء"
And if you've ever been in a meeting where you play sort of meeting "chicken,"
اذا كنت فى اجتماع من قبل، يتوفر فيه نوع من المرح
you're sitting there, looking at the person, waiting for them to look away,
كنت جالسا هناك ، تنظر الى شخص ،منتظراً منه أن ينظر بعيدا ،
and then quickly checking the device.
ثم سريعا تتحقق من الجهاز.
Although you can see the gentleman up on the right is busting him.
وعلى الرغم من أنه يمكنك أن ترى هذا الرجل الجالس على اليمين قد امسك به.
"The stretch."
"التمدد"
OK, the gentleman on the left is saying, "Screw you,
حسنا ، هذا السيد المحترم على اليسار يقول: "تبا لك ،
I'm going to check my device."
ساقوم بتفحص الجهاز ".
But the guy, here, on the right,
ولكن الرجل ، هنا على اليمين ،
he's doing the stretch.
فأنه يستخدم استراتيجية التمدد
It's that reeeee-e-e-each out, the physical contortion
وهو أن يمد يده
to get that device just below the tabletop.
للوصول للجهاز من اسفل الطاولة
Or, my favorite, the "Love you; mean it."
أو، المفضلة لدى ،"أحبك, أقصد ذلك".
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Nothing says "I love you"
فلا شيء يقول "أنا أحبك"
like "Let me find somebody else I give a damn about."
مثل " دعنى اجد شخصاً آخر اهتم به "
Or, this one, coming to us from India.
وصلتنا هذة من الهند
You can find this on YouTube,
يمكنك ان تجدها على موقع YouTube،
the gentleman who's recumbent on a motorcycle
الرجل الذي يرقد على دراجة نارية
while text messaging.
بينما يرسل رسالة نصية قصيرة
Or what we call the "sweet gravy, stop me before I kill again!"
أو ما نسميه "كسب الحلو ، اوقفنى قبل أن أقتل من جديد!"
That is actually the device.
في الواقع هذا هو الجهاز.
What this is doing is, we find a --
ما نقوم به ، وجدنا --
(Laughter)
(ضحك )
a direct collision --
تعارض مباشر --
we find a direct collision between availability --
وجدنا تعارض بين التوفر --
and what's possible through availability --
وما أمكن من خلال ما توافر --
and a fundamental human need -- which we've been hearing about a lot, actually --
وحاجة إنسانية أساسية -- التي كنا نسمع عنها كثيراً --
the need to create shared narratives.
وهى الاحتياج الى وجود حكايات مشتركة
We're very good at creating personal narratives,
اننا جيدون جدا فى صنع حكايات شخصية
but it's the shared narratives that make us a culture.
ولكن الحكايات المشتركة هى ما تصنع ثقافتنا.
And when you're standing with someone,
عندما تكون واقف مع شخص ما ،
and you're on your mobile device,
وتقوم بتفحص جهازك النقال ،
effectively what you're saying to them is,
ما تقول لهم حرفيا هو ،
"You are not as important as, literally,
" انك فعلا لست بأهمية
almost anything that could come to me through this device."
اى شئ يمكن ان يصلنى عبر هذا الجهاز. "
Look around you.
انظر حولك
There might be somebody on one right now,
قد يكون هناك شخص ما في الوقت الحالي ،
participating in multi-dimensional engagement.
مشارك في إشتباك متعدد الأبعاد .
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Our reality right now is less interesting
واقعنا الآن أقل متعة
than the story we're going to tell about it later.
من القصة التى سوف نقولها عنه في وقت لاحق.
This one I love.
أحب هذة.
This poor kid, clearly a prop --
هذا الطفل المسكين، من الواضح أنه قوى--
don't get me wrong, a willing prop --
لا تفهموني خطأ ، انه على استعداد قوى --
but the kiss that's being documented kind of looks like it sucks.
لكن القبلة التى يتم توثيقها تبدوا سيئة.
This is the sound of one hand clapping.
هذا صوت يد واحدة تصفق
So, as we lose the context of our identity,
لذا ، ونحن نفقد سياق هويتنا ،
it becomes incredibly important
يصبح من المهم جداً
that what you share becomes the context of shared narrative,
ان ما تشارك به يصبح في سياق الحكايات المشتركة ،
becomes the context in which we live.
يصبح السياق الذي نعيش فيه.
The stories that we tell -- what we push out --
القصص التى نحكيها
becomes who we are.
تصبح ما نحن عليه
People aren't simply projecting identity,
ببساطة نحن لا نقوم بإبراز الهوية ،
they're creating it.
نحن نقوم بصنعها.
And so that's the request I have for everybody in this room.
وهذا هو طلبى من الجميع في هذه القاعة.
We are creating the technology
نحن نبتكر التكنولوجيا
that is going to create the new shared experience,
التى ستقوم على خلق تجربة جديدة مشتركة ،
which will create the new world.
والتى ستقوم بخلق العالم الجديد.
And so my request is,
ولذلك فطلبى بكل بساطة هو ،
please, let's make technologies
من فضلكم ، دعونا نصنع التكنلوجيا
that make people more human,
التي تجعل الناس أكثر إنسانية ،
and not less.
وليس أقل
Thank you.
شكرا لكم .